uh
i forgot about this the hot potato hello
everyone welcome back to another episode
of hermitcraft in the last episode
impulse managed to sneak this thing
into my inventory and i
have to put on a resource pack which he
has given me so let's do that right now
it's called joke pack version 4. it's
been through four versions
doesn't seem that different wait
nothing seems that different now i'm
gonna be uh wait oh wait
okay there's there's some things that
are different
path blocks are lava
and there's random dirt oh
the shulker boxes are dirt blocks oh
that's gonna be really annoying okay so
for one full episode and what is going
on here
they've changed
is this water
they've changed water to cranberry juice
cranberry juice how weird
um okay so there's a few things to get
there's a few things to get used to oh
that's gonna freak me right out
yeah so the path blocks a lava
shulker boxes are dirt and i'm sure
there's going to be other things that
i'm totally going to find out along the
way why is there half a fish
i think out of everything that's the
weirdest thing what is it wait
all of the poppies are now salmon that's
really weird okay
so
if you see something weird in this
episode it's probably the hot potato
punishment but speaking of the hot
potato we will actually have to try and
get this
into somebody else's inventory in this
episode we can't we can't be dealing
with this forever so i'm gonna have to
think of something so we'll probably do
that a bit later in the episode because
i haven't got any ideas right now or a
method to sneak it into anyone's
inventory and also no one's on the
server there's no one here it's it's
literally just me on my own because
everyone is away at my con live so
i'm gonna have to wait for people to get
back anyways right so let's crack on
with today's episode we've got quite a
lot to do i've been doing some stuff in
the background in this barrel
i promise you these are not dirt blocks
these are actually all shulker boxes
all shulker boxes as you can see they
are full of dyes i have one of each
color
and
they're actually dyed why isn't my
pickaxe working the reason that i got
all of these dies is because i have
quite a lot of work to do over at sahara
that's right it's time to go full
business mode back at sahara why can't i
fly
wait hold on
firework golden carrot ah
golden
mike
my golden carrots and rockets have been
swapped around oh my goodness there's
cranberry juice everywhere
uh this is going to take some getting
used to in fact i don't think i'm going
to get used to this at all as i was
saying we've got a lot of business to
take care of at sahara since i've been a
hippie it's been slightly neglected
and if we open this we have got we've
been paid in coal but it looks like
someone has bought another sahara now
membership
no these are diamonds
there's a lot of texture changes there's
a lot of texture changes wait
oh
these are actually
coal and diamonds have been swapped
this is going to be an absolute
nightmare how am i meant to do it look
at all the dirt in my adventure
this is a nightmare but if that means
wait hold on no yeah fireworks are
carrots and carrots are fireworks
oh boy right let's go back to sahara
i've probably chosen the wrong day to
have this punishment take place this is
going to be so confusing for those of
you that don't really know what a
resource pack is it changes the texture
and names of things in game so this is
just gonna confuse me and it's probably
gonna confuse you as well
sahara sweet sahara is out of deals
again so we're also going to have to
make some more sahara now deals
but i think if we look over here this is
our
thing oh mumbo's made a lot of coal i've
also made a lot of i sold four saharan
nails and iskgao has also sold a lot for
a lot of coal but i
just sold another one meaning
i
am in the lead i don't know how many
wait how many we sold one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten eleven
we've made one thousand one hundred
diamonds from this project this is
amazing but we do need to stock up on
the sahara now deals anyway the place i
was going is over here because i keep
getting confused okay these dirt blocks
are meant to be dyes because this is a
concrete maker that isgow's made and
he's asked me to get all the dyes that
we need to make what is going on here
with the water
i'm guessing all i've got to do
is fill up all of these boxes with the
correct dies yeah this was a really bad
day to turn all of my shulker boxes into
dirt
because i can't tell
look at this i can't tell what colors
what
okay so let's fast forward this because
i think this is going to take a really
long time i've only actually shown you a
small bit
don't tell his scout but i actually
accidentally put most of the dyes in the
wrong box and i had to go behind the
scenes take it all out and put it back
in again so it took even longer than i
expected
man he didn't make this easy did he oh
okay
they are all loaded up with the correct
one i messed up as you probably could
have seen by the time lapse that uh i
put all of these in the wrong one
because it's the box on the left and i
was putting it on the box on the right
because it's the box on the right on
this one but the box on the left on this
one confusing iskal okay so i think it's
not loaded up with enough gravel and
sand so even though i've supplied all of
the right dies it definitely doesn't
have enough of the other stuff that i
need for this so i'm going to see if i
can find some sand and gravel to load
this up with it looks like we've run
completely out of gravel so i'm going to
have to go and collect some more
mama this guy may have done the the
redstone part of this but
there's still a there's a lot of
collecting involved i guess that's where
i come in anyway
while we're here i noticed that iskall
didn't get rid
of this our lovely telescope to check on
our friend now
we desperately do need to check on our
friend
because
he's been sighted
our friend with you know feathers and
eggs has been he's been seen
uh he was seen on one of impulse's
videos
look now it's right here this is gonna
be the door what
is
what what's happening
no poultry man
what
so i thought i would check up on him
to see if he's still there
nope
no
there's
nobody there
ha
it looks like
he's returned
we'll have to keep an eye out for him
but we must continue our quest
to sort out this gravel
[Music]
all right i know it looks like i've just
collected a bunch of dirt but each one
of these is a shulker box of sand or
gravel and this is exactly what we need
to put in this machine here
and i've also been instructed how to use
this it's all very exciting okay
so now we've
sand
gravel
iskell has gone and made some changes to
this because i noticed a slight bug with
it and he came and fixed it because
basically these things were just
bouncing back and it wasn't working
properly so while i was collecting this
is scale fixed this and now
it's time to craft up some concrete and
the goal here by the way for those of
you that aren't sure what we're doing
here we're going to stock sahara with
concrete which is actually the first
shop to actually sell concrete it's
amazing because everyone loves these
blocks but no one actually sells them so
this is a good business venture
let's get cracking with it and we let it
do its thing oh i also need to flick all
of this is like a dream come true i get
to flick all the levers and that starts
loading up all of these there's a lot of
admin involved in order to get this to
work but the second that that's out of
the way
we are flying
iskall
i need an adult
it's it's broken i need someone that
knows redstone what have i done wrong
nothing i've done nothing wrong
i'll tell you what i'll do forward slash
sermon
iskall he he knows what he's doing he
knows he's he's fixed it there was
something wrong he said this piston was
powered all right problem solved
issue resolved
time to keep on loading stuff in i think
it's stuck again
this gal
it's let's go
i stand here next to the crafting tables
i select what color i want to make we'll
make white concrete since it's right
there
it then comes up i then find it
in here somewhere
i'm pretty sure that cyan terracotta is
not supposed to be there
now i'm i'm no redstone expert but i
don't think that's meant to be there
there you go then that gives me exactly
what i need to craft that up i press it
again
it gives me everything i need to craft
it i need to learn where this
thing is there we go and basically you
keep pressing exactly what you need
i guess i can press as many as i like
oh
no too many too many too many
mistakes i can't craft it fast enough
uh-oh
this isn't good
this is what happens when you get
carried away
okay so i think the lesson learned today
is one at a time
this girl just joined oh my goodness he
didn't see what i just did
okay so now that we have some concrete
powder i've been told all i need to do
is stand here and right click
like that
and then it loads it into the machine
i believe which is what it's doing now
i'm confused what the heck
[Music]
to hear brian
wait a minute
wait a minute that's totally just a
zombie right
yeah this is
that scared me oh no
so it pushes it down
blows it up
goes down the water stream and then it
should end up up here
as it comes around brilliant so now
i literally just have to stand here for
a few hours to
make all this stuff up
all right i guess i'll see you guys in a
few hours time
okay this is pretty cool you can't
really tell because i'm mostly creating
white concrete but if you look carefully
you can see that it's kind of like 3d
printing the concrete downwards and then
it's going so fast this time-lapse that
you can't even see the tnt exploding but
it's destroying it as it reaches down
what the bottom and then it all falls
down and ends up in the back it's
awesome
i've only been doing this
for 84 years
and we're just about finished
let's turn this off
there we go and there's there's concrete
galore in here i have been storing some
concrete here
and i've got a bunch of it in here
some in here like there is a lot of
concrete this took a really long time to
get together in fact it took 84 years
i'm now an old man
i've got a beard it took so long
um yeah so now i'm an old man
i also have produced some sahara now
boxes so what i've got is only five
actually only five boxes because the
truth is i'm running out of stuff
i i don't actually have much to put in
if i if we go over the cranberry sea the
firework got me again if we go over the
cranberry sea into my base to look at my
chest monster that we've got going on
here
there's not a lot of useful blocks going
on not a lot that i can actually put in
a sahara now box so
yeah this isn't good there's not there's
not a lot of really useful things
however i have managed to scrimp and
save and i have managed to produce five
boxes so let's price these up the
biggest one is this the box of white
concrete now we're going to be stocking
this at sahara for two diamonds per
stack so let's price all of these up
concrete is going to be 25 diamonds
because that's just under half price
the glass is is not called not sand
anymore six diamonds
ice is awesome five diamonds
the sand is five diamonds and the
rockets which are actually golden
carrots because the resource pack
they're going to be
10 diamonds
and this actually gives me a really good
idea i know how i'm gonna get rid of
this the hot potato and i know what my
next punishment's gonna be the person
who ends up with this hot potato so
let's rename this
hot potato
speak to
green there we go and how we're going to
get rid of this is we're going to use
sahara now sahara now is so popular we
can't even stock it
so what i'm going to do
is put in all of these there we go now
what i'm going to do is actually rig
this so that if you press this button
it launches one of those out now and
it's actually going to drop her the hot
potato right here so while they're
cycling through it and they hear all the
buttons and the beeps and the boops
they probably won't notice this sneak
into their inventory so i'm actually
gonna have to do something quite
dangerous here
these are golden carrots yeah okay i'm
gonna have to break in
i'm gonna have to break in here and i'm
gonna need to take a redstone output
from this machine that i don't know how
it works this is dangerous
so i need to take
i need to take this redstone torch
because when you hit that that goes off
so if i take it
by
doing that
there we go okay so i could take the
output from this
and then bring it underneath
this thing here
oh this is genius this is absolutely
genius i tell you
i take the dropper
pop that there pop the hot potato in the
hopper put that on there there's no need
for any carpet as long as this is
powered this should work so in theory
look at that look at that
that is the simplest
hot potato
ever
but this should in theory work
okay so let's just pretend that i'm
shopping i'm shopping at sahara right i
come in here and let's i have to have
something in my hand let's let's pretend
i have a full inventory now this is a
bit of a risk and by a bit this is a
huge risk because if i have a full hot
bar
then i'm not going to notice oh my
goodness i didn't notice that at all
you cannot tell that that goes in but
there is a risk if i have an empty hand
it goes straight into my hand
and i'm gonna get caught
so there's a big risk with this one but
there always is with a hot potato there
always is so i just need to hope that
the person that comes and shops here has
absolutely a full
well maybe inventory bar a few places
and then when they go ahead and they
open this they might notice it there
this is gonna be good so i think as long
as they don't notice it go in their hand
they've they've been got
so this is good right so
i've reached
i just hot potatoed myself
trying to
trying to check the deals okay well i
think we've just confirmed
this works so yeah anyway let's have a
look we got the golden carrots here
and we got the ice yeah like i i've
stocked this thing up i've stocked up
well a little bit
so
let's hope
that this works
hot potato in there
leave it be
job is done
whoa
i was just flying above here
and there's like a golden there's a
there's a golden nugget on the floor how
do i how do i pick it up
how do i
how do i beat this thing
how do i win
hello
how do i get how do i get the nugget oh
treasure token
gold nugget okay
um
i have no idea what these are for
that's weird i wonder what these are for
treasure token is there a treasure hunt
on the server
is there a treasure hunt oh there's
another one
there's another one okay how do
these are a bit of a paint and get
yeah there's another treasure token
there's got to be some more around here
oh wow
okay so that's why there's fish that's
terrifying
i need to find some more there we go
there's another one
oh this is fun do they lead somewhere
where's the next one then there was one
along here
is it this direction i feel like if this
is a this is like a treasure hunt thing
oh look yeah yeah there's another one
oh this is so exciting i think the
trail's gone cold i've been looking
around for the next one but i don't see
it maybe i went the wrong way i don't
know this is weird
oh no there's another one i don't see
anymore and they don't seem to lead
anywhere
so i'm not sure what oh no wait i found
another one
they're everywhere they these are not in
a line i
i'm really not sure what these are about
i guess i'll just hold on to these for a
while i'm not sure i hope i'm not
spoiling anything by picking these up
either way i'm gonna head back to hermit
land oh i'm still an old man i think i'm
gonna have to be an old man for the rest
of this episode gonna head back to
hermit land now i know we've done quite
a lot of sahara related architect things
but
uh i've been so busy being a hippie
that honestly i haven't really had the
time and a lot of you will be wondering
why did it take me a week to upload a
video because i saw quite a few comments
saying when's the next upload grian well
i have been extraordinarily busy in real
life but not to worry there's more
episodes to come we're now back at it
lots of people were over in doing the
minecon live panel and it's kind of been
it's kind of been empty on the server so
i thought i'd take a little bit of a
break get some stuff done in the real
world before i dive back into the
minecraft one because i actually have
a very
very very big idea
for the next thing to do on hermitcraft
and it's going to be
amazing
that was a that was a good travel talk
wasn't it
but i'm not going to share the idea just
yet because i need to make sure that
everyone wants to get involved before i
do it because this is going to be
a really big server thing
oh the reason that i was coming over
here is because i was wondering if
there's anything over in hippie land
here that i can use to make uh another
sahara now box because look i've got
several chest monsters over here and
i've actually got a whoa
a what
chickens
what have they done to my chickens
and why are the eggs arrows
oh that's weird no i don't like that no
i don't like that
i will be glad to be rid of this
resource pack
my punishment is nearly over
and my punishment for the next person
who finds the hot potato well
let's just say
quack
so i can't wait to see who gets the hot
potato but it's gonna be funny but quack
is the only thing that i'm gonna say to
you
right let's let's see what's going on
here i want to get a good look at oh no
oh
oh they're oh they're faceless they're
hideous
wait they're me
they're green chickens
i don't know what they mean by this
that i i i hope they don't mean to
insinuate anything that i have anything
to do with poultry not
i don't i don't like that insinuation at
all
at all
i i'll have you know i have absolutely
nothing i have no problem with killing
chickens
uh this this doesn't affect me
whatsoever
no sir
no siree
oh that scared me either way it doesn't
it doesn't look like i have much to
actually contribute in terms of a sahara
now but so i think i'm gonna have to
just leave it at at five boxes
yeah look at all this junk
no there's nothing useful here and what
about here yeah absolute
nonsense junk okay i think we may
actually have to do some item collecting
at some point because it's not looking
good let's leave let's leave hippie land
for now and check out what's new in the
hermit land
deposit your nuggets
there's nuggets right here what is this
nfd i don't know what this means
diamonds out deposit throw it in here
well that hasn't worked
in here
[Music]
oh there's music
ah
i got coal
no wait coles are diamonds i got a
diamond it's very hard to get excited
about coal
even though i know that this is a
diamond look it says underneath
minecraft diamond
just because it looks like a coal it's
hard to get excited okay so it is a
treasure hunt you find these nuggets you
pop them in here
and then you get a good old jingle
[Music]
oh
we're gonna time a block if this is a
money printing machine no wait
oh wait diamond blocks are real oh
this is so exciting
[Music]
oh my goodness
ah
nothing
okay oh man this is this is the best
done
[Music]
no okay okay okay one more two more we
got two more two more nuggets
oh
nothing last one
done
go on go on
yay we got another diamond oracle oh
that was so good so we got we got
man we got 11 diamonds for doing nothing
that's amazing and there's there's these
nuggets absolutely everywhere
everywhere
someone's glued this to the floor
there we go
this is so exciting
well i guess i'm going to be collecting
a few tokens
there's another one on the floor they're
everywhere okay i need to leave some for
everyone else so i'm not i'm not gonna
look i can see three one two
and there's one over there three but
i've i've got to be i've got to be
selfless here and let everyone else find
a token so we're gonna do this one last
token and we're gonna leave the rest for
everyone else to find all right last
last token
ah
well that's a sad note to end this
episode on i am that we've actually
despite it being a bit of a a tech heavy
episode we've actually got quite a lot
done we restocked sahara now we've
passed on the hot potato i am fed up of
this resource pack in fact as it is the
end of the episode i will take off the
resource pack there we go oh
end of the episode everything is back to
normal we are back on track we are
recording hermitcraft we are having fun
we have made a lot of concrete we have
stocked up sahara now we've got rid of
the hot potato and
we even
have seen that our feathered friend
has
he's he's he seems to be lurking around
so keep an eye out for poultryman
everyone
he might be making a return
all right thank you very much for
watching as always and good bye